Zak (Zaheer) Rasafali

Senior Project Manager, L&T Infotech



Contact

Address

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, 600042

Phone

984-064-3042

E-mail

r.zaheer.abbas@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/zak-zaheer-rasafali-08

Skills

Cost Control

Project Scheduling

Client liaison

Planning and Coordination

Excellent Communication

Decision Making

Multitasking Abilities

Organization & Time Management

Excellent

Conflict Resolution

Very Good

Training and Development

Good

Experienced Senior Project Manager with PMP certification ready to provide strong direction and strategy to Scrum teams across development units. Highly experienced in leading ETL & Big Data Scrum Teams and keen abilities in business management including budgets, scheduling, and business development. Consistently successful in client management. Looking forward in leading big programs with multiple delivery units.

Work History

2020-08 -Current

Senior Project Manager

L&T Infotech, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

- Developed project plans and managed project scope using methodologies to guide projects from conceptualization to implementation and maintenance.
- Directed changes to project scope and cost and implemented appropriate change management processes to keep project on track.
- Oversaw internal and external projects by reviewing activities, maximizing efficiency and increasing collaboration and communication transparency.
- Outlined work plans, determined resources, wrote timelines and generated initial budgets as part of project scope determination.
- Supported and executed simultaneous delivery of various ETL and Big Data Projects.
- Empowering 4 project teams for ETL/Big Data technical development in Agile environment.
- Kept project on schedule and within budget while serving as project leader.
- Recorded all project costs and expenses and aligned with project budget.
- Monitored contracts and service level agreements to identify potential risks and implement mitigation actions to protect development process from unforeseen delays and costs.
- Directed offsite team design, transition and standardization of processes, resulting in maximized team resources and management.
- Produced reports and updated customers and senior leaders on progress and roadblocks.

2019-03 -2020-07

Project Manager/Senior Business Analyst

Atos Syntel, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

- Developed and initiated projects, managed costs, and monitored performance.
- Fostered relationships with teams to promote positive working relationships.



- Updated operational methods, oversaw accounting procedures, tracked information and compiled data to improve efficiency.
- Oversaw high profile projects for by planning, designing, and scheduling phases.
- Identified plans and resources required to meet project goals and objectives.
- Modified and directed project plans to meet organizational needs.
- Identified, reviewed and applied policies and procedures.

2013-10 -	Senior Business Analyst
2019-03	Atos Syntel, Phoenix, Arizona
2010-06 -	Business Analyst
2013-10	Atos Syntel, Chennai, Tamil Nadu
2007-10 -	Service Manager, Priority Banking
2010-06	Standard Chartered Bank, Chennai, Tamil Nadu
2005-09 -	Assistant Manager
2006-07	ICICI Bank, Chennai, Tamil Nadu

Education

2001-08 -	Bachelor of Technology: Information Technology
2005-05	Crescent Engineering College (Anna University) - Chennai

Certifications

2021-10 Project Management Professional (PMP)

Interests

Movies

Watching Sports